Guide to the Architect & Engineer Collection circa 1790-1989 PR 3
New-York Historical Society
Architect & Engineer collection
circa 1790-1989
New-York Historical Society
PR 3
20 Linear feet Over 1,500 architectural and engineering drawings
The collection consists of approximately 1,500 drawings in many media, including ink and graphite drawings, renderings, sketches, blueprints, and lithographs representing works by more than 150 locally and nationally prominent architects and engineers.
Provenance
The collection came from over 60 sources. The bulk of the collection was the result of donations.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers, by appointment only.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 20 photocopies per day per person. Suitability of the original for photocopying is at the discretion of the staff. Neither blueprints nor tracings can be copied under any circumstances. Duplication of large-format items will be done by the house photographer. See Print Room guidelines for details.
Scope and Content Note
The collection includes more than 1,500 architectural and engineering drawings from 1811-1989. They are in many media, including ink and graphite drawings, renderings, sketches, blueprints, and lithographs. Of the approximately 1,400 entries in database, most entries represent one item or a group (less than 10) of related items.
Works by more than 150 locally and nationally prominent architects and engineers are represented. Designers include: Squire Whipple; Charles Bulfinch; Carrère & Hastings; Ernest Flagg; John Haviland; Peabody & Stearns; James Renwick Jr.; Richard Upjohn; Calvert Vaux; Edward Pearce Casey; Delano & Aldrich; Wendel Bollman; and Warren & Wetmore. There are usually fewer than 10 drawings by any one architect or engineer. However, the collection includes over 50 Gilbert Elevated Railway drawings, over 100 reprographic documents and original drawings by Henry P. Davidson.
The file contains such diverse material as Interborough Rapid Transit Company subway system drawings; U.S. Capitol drawings by John Trumbull, ca. 1800-1820; engineering schemes for the Gilbert Elevated Railway, ca. 1875; estate landscaping plans by Schermerhorn & Foulks, ca. 1910; Corps of Engineers plans for the Solomons Lump Light Station in Maryland, 1894; and designs for structures on Long Island by Christian F. Rosborg, 1920s-1930s. An 1858 plan for Central Park, drawn by George Waring, is also included.
The bulk of drawings feature New York architectural or engineering subjects. However, the file also includes drawings of: Memorial Continental Hall of the Daughters of the American Revolution, Alexandria Aqueduct, Walters Art Gallery, Olivet College buildings, the U.S. Chancellery building in Paris, and many churches located in Virginia, Rhode Island, Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Maine, and Connecticut. Important New York subjects include: Castle Williams, Brooklyn Bridge, Astor Residence, American Radiator Building, Armory, Academy of Arts, Bowling Green Park, Battery Park, Carnegie Garden, City Hall, Halls of Justice, Customs House (Merchant Exchange), Union Square station, Manufacturers Trust Company building, Croton Aqueduct, Harlem River Bridge, Chapin School, Fort Diamond, New York Life Insurance Company Building, West Side improvement plans, New York sewers, Manhattan Market, Federal Hall, Apthorp Apartments, Verrazano-Narrows Bridge, Holland Tunnel, various residences, subway and transit lines, and commercial and factory buildings.
Arrangement
These series are based on the name of the architect, engineer and/or artist. Unattributed work is filed in the Unknown Creator series, and arranged thereunder by project name or building type (i.e. churches of Brookline Massachusetts are filed in series number 181, name architect and/or artist is unknown). Related materials within series are grouped into sets. Miscellaneous architecture and engineering drawings are grouped and housed together.
Hughson Hawley watercolor renderings are cataloged under series 035 with the exception of the renderings of The New-York Historical Society which are cataloged under the architecture firm Renwick, Aspinwall & Russell (series 092). Watercolor renderings of the Armory (Powell C. Karr, architect) and the New-York Life Insurance Company (McKim, Mead & White, architect) are cataloged under series 035. With the exception of the drawing mentioned above, Hughson Hawley renderings that are part of other collections, such as the Cass Gilbert collection or the Post collection, are not described in this database. Series 108 includes forts for which the architect/engineer/artist is unknown, except in the case of drawings by Henry Mehles which are also included in this series (name of fort unknown) and reproductions of miscellaneous fort drawings. Other series numbers are assigned to forts for which the architect/engineer/artist is known (see series 014 and 191). Series number order does not correspond to the alphabetical order of names of the architects/engineers/artists.
The collection is arranged in 241 series, alphabetically by architect, firm, or building.
Related Material
Works of Alexander Davis, Cass Gilbert, John McComb, Calvin Pollard, Emery Roth, Emery Roth & Sons, McKim, Mead & White, George B. Post, James W. Martens, William Delano, and John B. Snook are distinct collections. For William Strickland watercolors, see the N-YHS museum collection (American Landscape and Genre Paintings in the New York Historical Society). For John Haviland's drawings of the Doctor Wilson's Church, Washington Square Philadelphia, see the McComb sketch book on plans for altering steeple of the Brick Presbyterian Church in New York, part of the N-YHS Manuscript Department. Naval architecture blueprints of Hudson River steamboats are in the Subject File. Architect's papers and some sketches are also in the Manuscript Department. Building renderings are also in the Department of Paintings, Sculpture, and Decorative Arts. Drawings related to N-YHS's buildings can be found in the New-York Historical Society archives.
Separated Material
In 2002, Photographs taken by Arthur Jennings and of buildings designed by Raymond Hood were removed from this collection and now constitute PR 135, the Arthur Bates Jennings Photograph Collection, and PR 148, the Raymond Hood Collection. Also in 2002, over 100 residential elevations, floor plans, and ornamental detail sketches made ca. 1850 by Brooklyn architect James W. Martens were removed to their own collection, PR 113, the James W. Martens Architectural Records Collection. In 2004, student drawings by William Delano and photographs of buildings by his firm were removed from this collection and now form PR 244, the William Adams Delano Collection. Several drawings by the firm of Delano & Aldrich for Battery Park remain in PR 003.
Drawings by Carstensen & Gildemeister, Mettam & Burke, Isaac F. Wood, and York & Sawyer of New-York Historical Society buildings can be found in the New-York Historical Society Archives (NYHS-RG 3).
Accruals Note
Additional materials that are received from time to time that are consistent with the broad characteristics of this collection will be added to the Architects and Engineers Collection.
Bridges.; Architecture, Domestic.; Libraries; Monuments.; Municipal buildings.; Public buildings.; Railroad bridges.; Railroads.; Row houses.; Schools.; Societies' buildings; Carriage houses.; Church.; City halls.; Commercial buildings.; Cottages; Railroads, Elevated.; Estate records.; Factories; Fortifications; History -- Societies, etc.; Baltimore (Md.); Bedford, N.Y.; Bronx (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Clarkesville (Ind.); East Orange, N.J.; Fordham Heights, N.Y.; New Haven (Conn.); Olivet (Mich.); Portland (Me.); South Orange, N.J.; Summit (N.J.); Washington (D.C.).; Dwellings.; New Brunswick, N.J.; Queens (New York, N.Y.); Rome (N.Y.); Connellsville (Pa.); Providence (R.I.); North Edisto (N.C.); New York (N.Y.); Newark (N.J.); Philadelphia (Pa.); Holland Tunnel (Jersey City, N.J., and New York, N.Y.); Engineers; Architects; Lithographs.; Blueprints (reprographic copies).; Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); Renderings (drawings); Detail drawings; Floor plans.; Elevations (orthographic projections).; Building plans.; Watercolors (paintings); Technical drawings; Apartment houses; Engineering drawings; Architectural drawings (visual works); London, England; Charlottesville (Va.); Local transit.; Long Island (N.Y.); Subways.; American Bridge Company; New Jersey Interstate Bridge and Tunnel Commission; New York State Bridge and Tunnel Commission; Atterbury, Grosvenor; Baxter, Charles (Architect); Bollman, W. (Wendel), 1814-1888; Buffalo and New York City Railroad Company; Bulfinch, Charles, 1763-1844; Casey, Edward Pearce, 1864-1940; Davidson, Henry P.; Delano & Aldrich; Delano, William Adams, 1874-1960; Dwight, Benjamin Franklin; Eckman, Julius, 1805-1874; Flagg, Ernest, 1857-1947; Gilbert, Rufus H.; Harkness, William; Harrison, Henry G.; Haviland, John, 1792-1852; Hawley, Hughson, 1850-1936; Heins & LaFarge; Hindley, William; Interborough Rapid Transit Company; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820; Lienau, Detlef; Ludlow & Valentine; Peabody & Stearns (Boston, Mass.); Peck, Howard M.; Rosborg, Christian F.; Schermerhorn, Richard, Jr., 1877-1962; Skidmore Owings & Merrill; Thompson, Martin E.; Trumbull, John, 1756-1843; Tudor, Frederic; Turnbull, W., Captain; Upjohn, Richard, 1802-1878; Vaux, Calvert, 1824-1895; Walker, Joseph, Jr.; Warren & Wetmore; Whipple, Squire, 1804-1888; Wright, Peter M.
- Abert, James William (See Warren, Gouverneur Kemble), (PR 3-196)
- American Bridge Company (See Gilbert Elevated R.R.) (PR 3-24)
- Arlen Realty & Development Corp., 8 items (PR 3-206)
  - Fordham Center, 1972 (Box PR 3-206)
- Atterbury, Grosvenor, ca. 152 items (PR 3-1)
  - City Hall, New York, NY (Box PR 3-1)
  - Seth Low Residence, Bedford, NY, [1907] (Box PR 3-1)
  - Unidentified Foundation Plan, New York, NY (Box PR 3-1)
- Auchmuty & Ludlow, 1 item (PR 3-2)
  - Unidentified Church, Elevation (Box PR 3-2)
- Baldwin Locomotive Works (See Gilbert Elevated R.R.) (PR 3-24)
- Bancker, Gerard, 1 item (PR 3-191)
  - Fort George, New York, NY, 1817 (Box PR 3-191)
- Baxter, Charles, 31 items (PR 3-3)
  - Unidentified Five-Story Factory Building, Elevations, Sections, and Floor Plans (Box PR 3-3)
  - Unidentified Five-Story Building, possibly Nos. 112-118 West 52nd Street, New York, NY (Box PR 3-3)
- Bellow & Aldrich, 1 item, (PR 3-212)
  - Monument for Henry Elias Howland, Walpole, NH, 1917 (Box PR 3-212)
- Berrian, James (See Lienau, Detlef) (PR 3-47)
- Biles, Alfred, 4 items (PR 3-4)
  - Proposed City Hall Remodeling, Floor Plans New York, NY (Box PR 3-4)
  - Courthouse, Floor Plan New York, NY (Box PR 3-4)
- Bollman, W. (Wendel), 1 item (PR 3-136)
  - Patent Suspension Bridge, Elevation and Section (Box PR 3-136)
- Bolton, Reginald Pelham, (PR 3-180)
  - Nagel Farmhouse (Century House), Excavation Plan, New York, NY, 1906 (Box PR 3-180)
  - Riverside Park and Drive, Plan for Solution to West Side Railroad Track Problem, New York, NY (Box PR 3-180)
- Bryant, G.J.F., 1 item (PR 3-183)
  - Quincy Hall, Boston, MA, 1840 (Box PR 3-183)
- Bulfinch, Charles, 2 items (PR 3-66)
  - Capitol of the United States, Washington, DC (Box PR 3-66)
- Busbys, Joseph, 1 item (PR 3-5)
  - Unidentified Building (Box PR 3-5)
- Cafferty & Buckley, 8 items (PR 3-226)
  - Lenygon & Morant Inc. Building, 24-26 E. 82nd Street, New York, NY, [1900] (Box PR 3-226)
- Carrére & Hastings, 3 items (PR 3-6)
  - Victory Arch, New York Memorial, New York, NY, 1918 (Box PR 3-6)
- Casey, Edward Pearce, 23 items (PR 3-8)
  - Memorial Continental Hall and other buildings for the Daughters of the American Revolution, Washington, DC, 1904 (Box PR 3-8)
- Chamberlain, William E., 1 item (PR 3-9)
  - Unidentified Building (Box PR 3-9)
- Chambers, Walter B., 1 items (PR 3-10)
  - Lucina Memorial Chapel, Rockville, CT (Box PR 3-10)
- Chanler, William Astor, 2 items (PR 3-194)
  - Waterworks, Tampico, Mexico, 1902 (Box PR 3-194)
- Clinton & Russell, 2 items (PR 3-11)
  - Graham Court Apartments, New York, NY, 1901 (Box PR 3-11)
  - Apthorp Apartments, New York, NY, [1906] (Box PR 3-11)
- Company B., N.Y. Vol. Engineers, 1 item (PR 3-101)
  - [Bridge Design], Seabrook, SC (Box PR 3-101)
- Corps of Engineers. Light House Board (PR 3-243), 1894
  - Solomons Lump Light Station, Maryland, 1894 July (Box PR 3-243)
    Scope and Contents
    16 plates of architectural drawings issued by the Office of the Light House Board. Gift, Helen J. Brown, 1928.
- Davidson, Henry P., 31 items (PR 3-12)
  - Proposed Alteration at West End Ave., New York, NY (Box PR 3-12)
  - 794-6-8 Tenth Avenue, New York, NY, [1888] (Box PR 3-12)
  - Unidentified Building on 53rd Street, New York, NY, [1888] (Box PR 3-12)
  - Church on Bushwick Avenue, Brooklyn, NY, 1903 (Box PR 3-12)
  - Unidentified Building on Tenth Avenue, New York, NY, [1888] (Box PR 3-12)
  - Wallace Lamp Factory, New York, NY (Box PR 3-12)
- De Boisforet, 1 item (PR 3-242)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
  The item was transferred from N-YHS's miscellaneous manuscripts collection (now known as the American Historical Manuscripts Collection, or AHMC) to the Architect & Engineer File in August 2017. Its original acquisition information is unknown.
  - [Floor Plan of the Royal Grounds in Jacmel, St. Domingue], circa 1790? (Box PR 3-242)
    Scope and Contents Note
    Document is in French.
- De Remer, Joseph Bell, 1 item (PR 3-13)
  - Residence of Mr. George Anderson, Somerville, NJ (Box PR 3-13)
- Delafield, Richard, 1 item (PR 3-14)
  - Drawbridge of Fort Richmond, 1849 (Box PR 3-14)
- Delano & Aldrich, ca. 3 items (PR 3-15)
  - Battery Park, New York, NY (Box PR 3-15)
- Douglass, David Bates, 6 items (PR 3-179)
  - Croton Aqueduct, New York, NY, 1846 (Box PR 3-179)
- Duclos, J.M., 1 item (PR 3-17)
  - Unidentified Market (Box PR 3-17)
- Duggin, Charles, 1 item (PR 3-18)
  - Three Houses on a Corner Lot, New York, NY (Box PR 3-18)
- Dwight, Benjamin Franklin, 12 items (PR 3-19)
  - Residence for F.G. Shaw, Esq., Elevations, Sections and Floor Plans, 1853 (Box PR 3-19)
- Eckman, Julius, 14 items (PR 3-224)
  - Proposed Alterations to Lenygon & Morant Loft Building, New York, NY, 1934 (Box PR 3-224)
  - Proposed Alterations to Lenygon & Morant Inc. Building, 1082 Madison Avenue, New York, NY (Box PR 3-224)
- Electric Railroaders' Association, 1 item (PR 3-86)
  - Rapid Transit Lines at East New York, Brookyln, NY, 1944 (Box PR 3-86)
- Elliot, Wm. P. (William Parker), 1 item (PR 3-232)
  - New Patent Office, National Gallery of American Manufactures and Agriculture, Washington, DC (Box PR 3-232)
- Finlayson, F. L., 6 items (PR 3-20)
  - St. Johns Chapel, New York, NY, 1914 (Box PR 3-20)
- Flagg, Ernest, 13 items (PR 3-21)
  - Savings Bank of Rockville, Rockville, CT, 1914 (Box PR 3-21)
  - Residence for Lewis G. Morris Esq., New York, NY, 1913 (Box PR 3-21)
- Formento, L., 1 item (PR 3-100)
  - Pianta Del Tempio Pel Culto Valdese, Turin, Italy, [1851] (Box PR 3-100)
- Forts, 46 items (PR 3-108), 1811-1909, undated
  - Fort Welles, Hilton Head, S.C., undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Original drawing showing plan of fort and various sections. Annotations about armament which lists weapon calibers, what they are mounted on, and where placed in fort. Scale 1"=100'. 10" x 13" sheet.
  - Set of Drawings by O. Ranfft, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    A set of 23 plates/prints from treatise on designs for military fortifications. Titled plates include reference to Cormontaingne's Front, Vauban's Front, Lefebvre's Method, Wentzel's Method, Polygonal system of Montalembert, Trace of the front of Coehorn's 1st system, Chasseloup's system, Haxo's system, Choumara's system. 21" x 15" sheets. (Plans formerly numbered by N-YHS as series PR 3-166.)
  - Set of Drawings of Unidentified Fortifications, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Set of 9 plates/prints. Untitled and unattributed. (Formerly numbered by N-YHS as part of PR 3-166.)
  - Fort Columbus?, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Original sketch in ink wash, ink, and graphite pencil, possibly part of plan of Fort Columbus on Governor's Island. Some annotations (and dimensions) barely legible in ink. Verso shows part of site plan with annotations; Annotations of verso include: Parapet 22 feet inside on the Top, towards North River, Furnace, Mag., etc. Scale 1"=10'. 19" x 24" sheet.
  - Fort George, 1774, 1817 (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Original drawing "copied" on October 4, 1817 by Jonathan or Joseph Ludlam (?) from a April 12, 1774 drawing by Gerard Bancker: "A Plan of Fort George in the City of New York made at the request of the Honourable Jno. Cruger Esq. [mayor] and the rest of the Committee appointed to fix on a place for building a government house." 14 1/2" x 22" sheet.
  - Plan of Fort George, N.Y., 1774, circa 1909 (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Labeled as "Design to be used as tablet to be placed in N.Y. Custom House by the N.Y. Society of the Order of the Founders and Patriots of America." Plan is a tracing of the Gerard Bancker plan of Fort George of April 112, 1774, apparently made by E.H. Hall. 8 1/2" x 7" sheet, mounted. Acquired by N-YHS: Gift of Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission, May 5, 1911, George N. Moran.
  - Fortress Monroe, 1862 (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    A reprographic, sepia print of a drawing dated 1862. An aerial view of Fort Monroe, showing labeled boats, and numbered buildings within fortress with corresponding illegible numbered annotations written at bottom left of drawing. Signed in ink by R.A. Leurs [?] in lower right corner. 10" x 12 3/4" sheet, mounted.
  - Plan of Ft. Keogh, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Original color drawing (ink, ink wash) of plan showing parade ground, infantry quarters, officer's quarters, hospital, calvary stables, etc. Scale 1"=320'. 10 3/4" x 15 3/4" sheet. Acquired: July 23, 1925.
  - [Front Elevation and Section of Fortress Wall], Hilton Head, S.C., 1863 February 6 (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Drawn by Henry Mehles, 2nd Lieutenant, Co. B, New York Volunteer Engineers,Hilton Head. Original drawing in color inks of elevation and section of wall of an unidentified fort. 12" x 19 1/4" sheet.
  - Front and Back View: Drawbridge and Pallisading, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Original drawing of elevation of drawbridge and fencing (palisading), perhaps by Henry Mehles [?]. Also include small section and plan detail of fence posts. Rough sketches of details on recto & verso in graphite pencil. 12 3/4" x 15 1/2" sheet.
  - Fort Independence, Kingsbridge, 1776-1779, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Rough sketch of unknown origin showing plan of Fort Independence. Not an historic drawing; could be a copy of an historic drawing. "Boosted 16 times", Labels include: parade ground, proposed extensions, parapet, bastion, rampart above ground, entrance, headquarters, etc., "L 10 S-12" written on verso in pencil 8 1/2" x 11" sheet.
  - A Plan of Fort Gansevoort New York, 1812?, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Copy of historic drawing. Shows plan and side elevation of fort. Scale 1"=30'. Copied from original on file in War Department in Washington D.C. See History NY City in War 1812-15. "L 3 M-39" on verso in pencil. 18" x 26" sheet. Acquired by N-YHS: May 12, 1902.
  - Bastion Du Roy, Raisant Partie De Lenceinte La Ville De Louisbourg (King's Bastion forming a part of the ramparts of the town of Louisburg), 1924, 1935 September 17 (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Photoreproduction from the Public Archives of Canada, Map Division, of "A plan of the King's Bastion, barracks, chapel and officers appartments from the National Library, Paris. Drawn and colored by Albert Almon, 1924." Includes elevation of barracks facing town and section details. Acquired by N-YHS: Gft of Major Howland Pell, October 16, 1935. 13 1/2" x 15" sheet.
  - Louisburg City, Drawn by Geo. Follings (?), A.D. 1745, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Photoreproduction. Drawing shows plots, British flag, fortress wall, cemetery, surrounding water and land, ships, etc. 14 1/2" x 17 1/2" sheet. Acquired by N-YHS: January 30, 1926.
  - Canso, Fourt, 1745, undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    Photoreproduction of historic drawing of Fort Canso with British flag and numbered annotations about various buildings and attributes of fort. By George Follings(?). 16" x 17 1/2" sheet. Acquired by N-YHS: January 30, 1926.
  - [Plans of Various Forts], undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-1)
    "Photograph from original [manuscript] in British Museum from Rev. John Miller's 'New York Considered and Improved 1695', edited by Victor Hugo Paltsis. Pub. at Cleveland, O. by Burrows Bros Co. 1904." Shows five plans of forts in NY: area of Albany, the fort of Albany, the fort of Schenectady (spelled Scanecthade), the Indian fort at the Flats, and Kingstone. 13" x 15 1/2" sheet. Acquired by N-YHS: November 7, 1945.
  - A Plan of Fort Diamond on Hendricks Reef, Harbor of New York, Dec. 1818 (Oversize), undated (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-2)
    Noted "copied from original plan on file in War Department in Washington D.C. Made for defense of New York City in 1812." Drawings include: Section of the Gateway; Section of the Front of the Work,; Section Showing the "Casmated" Rooms, Gallery, and Area of Magazine; Perpendicular Section Showing the Embrasures and Tiers, Interior View of Front Wall & Rear Wall, & Plan. 22" x 40 1/4" sheet. Acquired by N-YHS: May 12, 1902.
  - Fort Sumter, South Carolina (Oversize), circa 1865 (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-2)
    Full title: "Fort Sumter, South Carolina, at the time of its capture, February 18th, 1865, showing the effects of the bombardment from Morris Island. To accompany the report of Maj. General Q.A. Gillmore, U.S. Vols, Comdg. Dept. of the South." Labels include: Elevation of Western Front, Horizontal Section, Elevation of North Eastern Front, Plan, etc. Scale 1"=20'. Lithograph by Julius Bien & Co. 29" x 36 1/4" sheet.
  - [Elevation and Section of Castle Williams/Fort Williams] (Oversize), [1811] (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-3)
    Watercolor rendering shows a longitudinal section, an aerial view section, and a side elevation. Components are labeled such as, Powder Magazines, Furnace for heating Shot, Stone Sentry Box, Bomb Proof Platform, etc. Scale bar given (1"=10'). Acquired by purchase from Abbott-Lenox, The Old Print Shop. 26 1/2" x 33" sheet, plus matting.
  - Plan of Fort Columbus on Governors Island (Oversize), [1811] (Drawer PR 3-108, Folder FF-3)
    Watercolor rendering shows an aerial view of Fort Columbus which has sides facing Red Hook, Long Island, the Bay & New York. Components are labeled, including a covered way to Castle Williams. Labels of components include: Gate 10 feet wide, with drawbridge & Slight Portcullis, Sally Port communicating with the Ditch by a vaulted passage 5 feet wide, Powder Magazine Bomb Proof, Two Bastions, etc. Scale bar given (1"=40'). Acquired by purchase at East Side Antiques Show, January 25, 1956. 26 1/2" x 33" sheet, plus matting.
- Freidin, Kleiman Associates, 4 items (PR 3-208)
  - Broadway Galleria, New York, NY, 1979 (Box PR 3-208)
- Friedberg, M. Paul & Partners, 2 items (PR 3-205)
  - City Hall Park, Delacorte Fountain Plumbing, New York, NY, 1977 (Box PR 3-205)
- Funk, H., 1 item (PR 3-22)
  - [Residence for Mr. & Mrs. Randell, Esq.] (Box PR 3-22)
- Garvin, Michael J, 5 items (PR 3-23)
  - Four Three Story Frame Buildings to be Located on Lots Situated on the South East Corner of Forest Ave. and 165th St., New York, NY, 1896 (Box PR 3-23)
  - House Situated on Forest Ave. and 165st St., New York, NY, 1893 (Box PR 3-23)